Steve Lucas

Address 705 Great Swamp Rd., Ridgeland, SC 29936

Phone (630) 740-9935

E-mail stevelucascs@gmail.com
References Available Upon Request



Professional Summary

I have a unique background, having studied a diverse set of interests including computer science, criminal justice, and engineering. Cybersecurity combines many of my interests and experience, making me motivated and well-suited for this field. I graduated with a **B.S. in Criminal Justice** and have a **CompTIA Security+ CE** certification.

Technical Skills

Cryptography NIST & NIMS Data Security Access Control **Business Continuity** Physical Security **Vulnerability Analysis** PKI Network Security Threat Analysis E-Discovery Web Development Policy & Compliance Risk Matrix Digital Forensics Scripting Windows Server SQL Server Blockchain Virtualization

General Skills

Problem Solving Emotional Intelligence Work Ethic Motivation & Aptitude Customer Service Accountability

Work History

2021-04 - **Information Technology Specialist**Current Quantum Endeavors, Inc., Bluffton, SC (Remote)

• Managing information security, data recovery, and general I.T. troubleshooting

2021-07 - Front-End Store Associate

2023-01 The Home Depot, Okemos, MI

- Assisted customers with questions, concerns, and loading their vehicles.
- Organized and cleaned the store and parking lot.

2019-04 - Salesforce Administrative Assistant

2019-08 Perma-Seal, Buffalo Grove, IL

- Helped migrate thousands of records from a legacy database (BizWiz) to a Salesforce i360 database.
- Validated and fixed hundreds of duplicate records, erroneous values, and other issues that resulted from previous migration to the database.
- Designed scripts for Salesforce-i360 to automate the process.
- Salesforce i360- Helped the accounting team by processing payroll and commissions

2017-06 -	Product and Partner Management Intern
2017-08	CDW Corporation Lincolnshire II

- I was part of a team that designed and implemented a new initiative to offer targeted discounts to customers based on what they had not purchased recently.
- Using records from CDW's SQL database, we selected products that would be offered at a discount to a customer through their portal on CDW's website.
- After launching the first iteration, we began analyzing the process and identified ways we could make it more efficient.
- As part of a side project, I experimented with Salesforce's sandbox feature and helped design a Salesforce implementation for another branch of the company.
- I gained valuable knowledge about the workings of Salesforce, its Apex programming language, and thoughts on the user experience from my coworkers.

2015-05 - Public Safety Auxiliary Officer

2016-05 Lake Superior State University, Sault Ste. Marie, MI

• Dispatch, Campus and Event Security, Emergency Preparedness.

2015-06 - Intelligence Center Intern

2015-08 Cook County Sheriff, Chicago, IL

• Intelligence Processing and Analysis, Data Input and Maintenance.

Education

2018-01 -	B.S. Criminal Justice , Minor: Information Security
2022-12	Grand Valley State University – Allendale, MI
2017-01 -	Computer Science – No Degree
2021-01	Grand Valley State University – Allendale, MI
2018-10 -	Full-Stack Web Development Certification
2019-02	Northwestern University – Chicago, IL
2014-10 -	Lake Superior State University
2014-10 - 2017-02	Lake Superior State University No Degree – Sault Ste. Marie, MI
	•
	No Degree – Sault Ste. Marie, MI
	No Degree – Sault Ste. Marie, MI Mechanical Engineering - 22 Credit Hours,
	No Degree – Sault Ste. Marie, MI Mechanical Engineering - 22 Credit Hours, Homeland Security - 56 Credit Hours,

Culturality and development of